Guide to the Abbot Family Papers, 1733-1999 and undated (bulk 1860-1910)
Abbot Family papers 1733-1999 and undated (bulk 1860-1910)
- Financial Papers Series, 1860-1916
  W.R. Abbot's business correspondence regarding the administration and expansion of Bellevue as well as various other real estate investments in Virginia and Kansas City. Contains savings book as well as an account book of Bellevue. Also includes receipts of taxes on property and of miscellaneous transactions with merchants for the daily administration of Bellevue.
  - Financial papers, 1860-1916, (11 folders) (Box 6)
  - Financial papers, 1860-1916, (15 folders) (Box 7)
  - Savings book, 1875 July-1890 July (1 vol.)
  - See also Account-book, 1895 March-1906 Sept. (1 vol.) in Box 8.
- Legal Papers Series, 1733-1950
  Insurance policies, deeds of trust, and land plats pertaining to Bellevue property and W.R. Abbot's property elsewhere in Virginia and in Kansas City; legal papers of Ellen Abbot's pre-Civil War residence in Georgetown; records of W.R. Abbot's partnership with J.P. Holcombe and his assumption of Bellevue subsequent to Holcombe's death; affidavits of family members recording receipt of inheritance; and original deeds of trust recording land grants made in Virginia to John B. Minor from Sir Thomas Carr of Topping Castle.
  - Legal papers, 1733-1950, (17 folders) (Box 7)
- Pictures Series, [1860s-1980s]
  60 photographs of the Abbot family and Bellevue, most of which are identified; one photocopy of a group picture of Abbots at Bellevue ([ca. 1900]) with names and dates labeled on reverse; 24 photographs of the Minor family; one photograph album containing mostly pictures of students at a turn-of-the-century women's college, including pictures of Lucy and Virginia Henderson; and 15 unidentified photographs of children, and young men and women. Series includes several cartes-de-visite and a few tintypes taken mostly at photographers' studios in Charlottesville and Lynchburg.
  - Photographs, [1860s-1980s], (5 folders) (Box 7)
- Oversized Material, 1878-1906 and undated
  - Account book, 1895 March-1906 Sept. (Financial papers series) (Box 8)
  - Letterbook, 1886 Aug. 27-1903 June 24 (Correspondence series)
  - Annie Minor's Civil War Memoir, undated (Miscellany series)
  - 1906 Typescript of the 1836 Diary of Charles Minor (Miscellany series)
  - Letter, 1878 from Charles Minor to My Dear Mother... (Correspondence series)
- Miscellany, 1857-1965 and undated
  Minutes of the Bellevue High School Literary Society; miscellaneous Bellevue-related papers including transcripts of a school-play and lists of academic journals on education; John Abbot's certificates of distinction at Bellevue; memorabilia of the Minor children comprised of verses by Cabell Minor and an elegy by Charles Minor (Jr.) on the death of Walter Scott written at Brookhill; a handwritten prayer and records of Brookhill school sessions (1857-1865). Includes Annie Minor's memoir of her experiences as a child during the Civil War (housed with oversized material in Box 8) and the Minor family Bible, an incomplete two-volume 1769 edition of the Authorized version with manuscript poetry and letters added to the front pages of the first volume.
  - Miscellany, 1857-1965 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Album, (1 vol.)
  - Abbot family Bible, (2 vol.) (Box 10)